all right greetings it's March 22nd 2023
we're in cohort three
and meeting nine in our second
discussion on chapter four of the
textbook
so last time we
went through some sections
and we have
um also a lot of questions that have
been addressed
so before we go back to the text or to
the questions
does anyone who's here
want to just like give any thought or
reflection
yeah what what um
what are you still looking to reduce
your uncertainty on
or whatever
yeah I'm just finding a lot of the
mathematics
um it's just not explained in a way that
disambiguates what you know what a
particular expression might be
um I've got certain uncertainties about
um some of the mathematical objects
themselves
um and then particularly on the section
on Taylor series and I feel that I have
a pretty good grasp on Taylor series
um that's feeling particularly opaque to
me which feels surprising
um
yeah I I'm finding it a slightly
frustrating chapter which sort of dives
into the maths but in some sense without
enough detail for me to really deeply
understand it
but maybe that's just a matter of time
thank you well
definitely when building on a sort of
meat and potatoes mathematical concept
someone with your expertise should not
be overly confused it should feel like
you have already been on the on-ramp to
understanding where this is going
because it's hard to imagine it'd be
clearer
for someone who is less familiar with uh
foundational pieces
so let's definitely keep that in mind
when we move through
okay
um
anyone else want to just like give any
overview thought on a section of four or
anything else on how there's
thinking about any aspect of it since
last week
then we will look at the questions
and then continue to move through
the text
I'm just looking at the previous video
to see where we ended
410.
okay any
other comments otherwise we're going to
go to 410
and continue
or a little bit before
okay
all right let's pull back to four four
and just please raise your hand or
um write in the chat with any thoughts
or questions so just looking at the the
questions
that were submitted in this uh cohort
like many of them involve the equations
um
for
seven eight
ten
and so on so these are ones where like
we can
um
look at at what was written for those
where things were written or otherwise
just like kind of
um given
the constraints on what we can do in 50
minutes just recognize these are like
important areas for there to be
asynchronous development on
but this looks like a great
um answer whomever has
written this and it's like a an example
of
um
how to address it asynchronously yes
Jonathan
yes this was my my contribution here
um the the explanation underneath
um I I still have some some questions
about it
um despite the fact that I think I Now
understand the the sort of the the
vector aspect so I I've created a an
overleaf document that sort of explains
all of this
um I'm I'm still slightly confused by
something quite simple here in the
expected free energy because there are
these um Tau
um indices floating around and Tau
indicates I think the the time the
moment in time so for instance s
um of P subscript uh Pi tau is the
probability of being in a given State
um at a particular time given that
you're undertaking some policy pie
um
and so there's a there's a Tau index
floating around but it's still not quite
clear to me in the calculation of the
expected free energy
um
what you do with that Tower index are
you are you summing over all of these
terms
um are you integrating over them it is
an expectation value over all of the
different time steps so that that was
the the one thing that was sort of least
clear to me here
foreign
yes great point
is it expected for energy as an
expectation of snapshot free energies is
it a expected free energy as the sum of
the expected futures
or is it even
the expectation at that last time step
alone
and the other ones are discarded
good points
in figure 4 3
we have
the discrete time
partially observable Markov decision
process pomdp and the continuous time
cousin
in the discrete time case
past present and future time steps
hidden states are explicitly predicted
and action sequences are explicitly
intervening in how hidden States change
their time
in contrast in the continuous time model
rather than predicting or even
explicitly mentioning past present and
future we see like x x Prime X double
Prime so the value of x and then the
higher derivatives
also known as the generalized
coordinates of motion and so this
amounts to making a Taylor series
expansion which is continuous around the
current time step
two different ways of dealing with
temporal depth
and the way that action selection
relates to temporal depth and they have
some in principle and in practices
strengths and weaknesses in different
settings
in 4.4
they're going to focus on the discrete
time model
the discrete time model has been
especially applied to
categorical cognitive decision making
whereas the archetypal case for The
Continuous time generative model is
continuous perception and action of like
a motor unit
and they can play well together as we'll
see in chapter 8 with Hybrid models
we could go
slower fast on equations but we'll just
try to like move through the whole thing
but many many of these
the work to be done
is making sure that we have
[Music]
um
high quality descriptions verbally which
we do for for many
due to many people's great work but
making sure that we have
verbal descriptions in the active
inference ontology
that are faithful
to the symbols
and then where people have questions
about what does this mean why is that
that way what if it were this way what
are the implications here those are all
great questions
and they can all be included in the
notes section for a given equation or in
the more General notes table
but for for many of the equations
including some of the super challenging
ones
[Music]
um
we have things written out which is very
good
um but just kind of
at the
um
skim
level
cat
is a categorical distribution so in this
section we're in a discrete setting so
like
the light is on or off the continuous
setting would be it's a continuous
variable between zero and one but in the
categorical setting we have categorical
distributions
and so we have certain
um ways of summing across them for
example instead of taking an integral
over a continuous distribution
um
action selection
ply
policy selection
is going to be guided by which policies
are most likely
most self-consistent most self-evident
most probable
lowest expected free energy
we're not proposing a reward or utility
function and then evaluating policies
based upon their expected reward
we're evaluating policies based upon
their self-consistency
and in fact the most probable ones are
the ones that lead to the lowest
expected free energy
so
more equations G is expected for energy
and even just looking at which variables
go into this
we see
a probability distribution over policies
that is defined
through and expected free energy
calculation
and this
G of Pi
it's a it's a function of
policy
and it is going to have this expected
free energy Construction
and we've seen expected free energy
before
in
equation 2.6
where
the part that's an expectation
that only involves preferences and
observations is pragmatic value
so
natural log of a distribution
expectation of a log
of something only involving observations
and preferences
here we have y tilde
here we have o tilde Y is sometimes used
for observations more in like a linear
regression setting o is like
observations but they're identical
and then
the other component is a and so it's
pragmatic value because that is the
alignment between the observations and
the preferences or expectations
the other component in this
decomposition of expected free energy is
a KL Divergence expected KL Divergence
between
two variational distributions two
distributions that we control Q
they're both x hidden States Through
Time X tilde
conditioned upon
and then they're very similar
here we only have Pi here we have pi and
Y
so this is the Divergence
with respect to whether adding
observations
updates are prior
if these two cues are the same
that's equivalent to saying there's no
space between the distributions
where we've parameterized x with or
without getting any observations
in other words the observations were
valueless
if the Divergence here is zero
whereas if the observations are really
impactful
on moving the distribution
then this KL Divergence is going to be
big
divergences are always non-zero
and then there's a negative here so the
more information gain the bigger the KL
Divergence the more that the
observations matter
the more this first term is going to go
negative
and so that specific policy
will have a higher epistemic value
Ali
uh yeah I just remembered a
clarification made by Ryan Smith in one
of his lectures about uh two concepts of
or rather two Notions of time used in
active inference literature uh one of
which is denoted by Tau and the other
one is denoted by T So a Tau is used for
the time about which we have a belief
and the examples he gives is for
instance I believe I am now in my car so
that would be S of Tau but I believe I
was in my kitchen 10 minutes ago would
be S Tau minus one where I believe I
will be at work in 20 minutes or
something would be S Tau plus one
but on the other hand we have t which
refers to the time at which a new
observation is given
so for instance as an example and after
turning on a light
I now
in other words essential believe that I
was in the kitchen for the last five
minutes right
so we can update our belief about all uh
all Taos or S of towns with each new
observation at each tease or at each
given observation times so uh briefly
one is the belief time and the other one
is the observation time so tau is used
for leaf times or the time about which
we have leaf and T is used for
observation times
thanks that's very helpful
is it accurate to say that T is like the
Click of our simulation
that's actually handing the new
observations in at a given moment T
after T but then especially in
sophisticated active inference where we
might be considering like the past
present and future at every t
we are reevaluating Towers at each tee
yeah I think we can reframe that in the
in this way as well
awesome
so
here we reach yes potentially with some
um Bumps and Jumps
the expected free energy for a policy in
terms of the pragmatic value
alignment of preferences with
observations and the expected
Information Gain the epistemic value in
terms of how much adding in observations
updates are variational distribution
about hidden States conditioned upon
that policy
here is more Focus
on how we get this KL Divergence
so here we see that KL Divergence
and there's just a few different
expansions and relationships around it
Jonathan
yeah so just zoom zooming into that
equation there
um there's an expectation
um over Q of O given pi
um and I I couldn't figure out how
that's calculated because I I understand
how one can get
um Q of s given o and Pi but it seems
that to calculate Q of O given Pi one
needs to marginalize or sum over the
states and I thought that that was the
whole reason for introducing Q in the
first place was because we we can't
um we can't same overall all external
States
the subscript notation may be
used in an unconventional way but I I
agree with you
on that
here in the inner queue
we have it about s
conditioned upon observations and
policies this doesn't seem contentious
yep that's fine yeah
but the subscript in 4.8 and I think
that was probably one of your questions
yeah yeah
that's the one
sorry with the terrible latent yeah yeah
yeah
um yeah we should look at the the Matlab
code for
wherever that comes into play to see how
it actually is done
or is
a separable variational quality
yeah like this is the just the inner
value
is the KL Divergence of how much
observations update
um uh add in to your changing beliefs
about s
but we're taking an expectation of that
over
expected observation sequences
which then begs the question of
needing to know the distribution of s
that would generate those probabilistic
envelopes of o
exactly yeah
well
one answer is
these are the analytical
um
ideals
for which there are strong analytical
guarantees
and then any given computational
implementation is going to use different
methods
to to implement this just procedurally
but that doesn't make the notation clear
and I I think these are some of the
kinds of artifacts hopefully cohort
after cohort
we can craft like a lookup table
and we've done this to a limited extent
just starting it but having a lookup
tables
for all the different
[Music]
um
shapes and squiggles
But continuing on site I hope that we
can at least see the rest of it
um
variational free energy F and expected
free energy G
variational free energy which we'll
recall from equation two to five
is a functional of Q the distribution we
control and Y the incoming data
so variational free energy is like the
real time unfolding model fit
and this is a quantity that's widely
used in statistics
expected free energy
uses similar
structure
and positioning
but it explicitly brings in two pieces
that aren't present in variational free
energy and those are observations which
haven't happened yet because we need to
talk about how informative we expect
observations that haven't occurred yet
to be
Information Gain epistemic value
obviously variational free energy is
only concerned with the actual data
point being acquired at the moment
and then secondly
the fact that we can take different
policy choices
and policy choices end up conditioning
for example
what pragmatic and epistemic value we
achieve or expect to achieve
so free energy
can have a variational free energy
formulation real time unfolding model
adequacy
or
projecting free energy into the expected
future
we need to invoke observations that
haven't happened yet
and
our agency in selecting alternative
policies
which then of course bear on the
epistemic and pragmatic value we
accomplish
here in 4 9
there are more decompositions of
expected free energy
that help see
previously recognized dialectics or
decompositions or trade-offs as actually
decompositions of the unified imperative
expected free energy so epistemic and
pragmatic value decomposition and an
ambiguity plus risk
no one can kind of walk through and see
what those mean or look at the natural
language
we can rewrite 4 7 in linear algebraic
form
here's four seven
here
is
for the categorical distribution
we can sum over policies
about the policies and the hidden States
Through Time
um
more details and calculations of
variational free energy
factorization and the mean field
approximate mean field approximation
these are some mathematical
technicalities but but
um
they are simplifying assumptions or ways
to approach this in the general case
this factorization is one of many
possibilities in variational inference
and as we talked about last time
variational inference is just one way to
do these calculations
and represents the simplest option and
in practice it's nuanced slightly and
there's like other approximations and
it's a whole thing
more information
on the letters that we know and love
a the tale of two densities
B how hidden States change Through Time
C prior beliefs about observations
which are preferences
and
the simple prior on the initial state to
kick the hidden State chain off
a little bit of
policy and belief updating few more
technical details
into active inference in continuous time
Box 41 on Markov blankets
a markout blanket for a given variable
with just those words the map territory
question is addressed Markov blankets
are about variables
comprises a subset of those that
interact with it if we know everything
about the subset knowledge of anything
outside the subset does not increase our
knowledge of the variable of interest
there are several
Bayesian message passing schemes
expounded on a lot further in other work
with fristin parts of rise at all
probably not
the most relevant to delve into right
now
but the important takeaway
is that by using a base graph
so by making a commitment to the figure
4.3 Lego set
if we choose to have nodes be random
variables and edges reflect
relationships amongst variables in a
certain way
then
we gain access to message passing
techniques
that make even large Bayesian graphs
with different parts of the graph
updating at different speeds and so on
there are software packages
that are able to in a defined
computational complexity setting
run inference on those base graphs
so yes bigger models all things being
equal take more time and more
computational resources to run
however there are some tremendously
scalable
high performance ways
to computationally implement
computation on these graphs
and they have
interesting analytical representations
and
they have
a growing
stat of tool kits
like reactive messagepassing dot JL by
the bias lab with Bert DeVries and
um his lab
this is like really cool
current work that's not even
outside of their lab and colleagues not
heavily used
in even active inference Publications
but
they have incredible recent work
and you can see how they're using
variational free energy in these
um
advanced settings
pulling back to consider message passing
qualitatively in the chapter whereas it
was introduced in this Markov blanket
box
um
message passing they'll be totally
looking oh thank you I will yeah uh
there's the bioslab site and I'll add it
to the figure four
the reactive message passing is like one
of their new pieces
where
um let's say you had two sensors and one
of them was being updated every second
and one was being updated every hour
well if you only could turn the clock
if you you might get into a situation
where you would either say well should I
update my model every second
and then over sample the slow variable
or should I sample my model every hour
and under sample the fast variable
and reactive message passing navigates
that by actually having nodes update on
demand
so you can have one node that's just
getting pinged every second and another
node that's getting updated on a
different time scale
and the computations on demand
so that allows you to have like lifelong
online learning for base graphs flexibly
with different rates of sensors
and and so those are the kinds of
toolkits like like
um
these models are not just being proposed
to promote theoretical unity in the
cybernetic Sciences
also there are powerful software
toolkits
that using these kinds of architectures
enable
so epistemic value pragmatic value
um message passing schemes
um
if anyone knows any takeaways from this
image please feel free because certain
things are like omitted
and also it uses like a lot of squiggles
and ease and different variables
um but
here we have a representation
of
a hierarchical
model so you can tell it's a
hierarchical model because you have like
I and you have this kind of cluster of
four
and you have I plus one
and you have errors getting passed up
and hidden State inferences getting
passed down
and so this would be like the sort of
Timeless representation of that modeling
hierarchy hierarchical base hierarchical
predictive processing architecture
um tilde through time so we're just
describing timelessly
here is the hierarchical Bayesian model
this can be rendered or unpacked through
time now we see that Tau minus one Tau
Tau plus one
as a function of time so instead of just
seeing it as like o tilde like a
sequence and seeing this as like a
skyscraper
this can be unrolled
in a procedural way using message
passing techniques
um okay are the rules for message
passing on a convoluted Bayesian Network
known
yes
this
paper
that I have just put in the chat here we
see figure 4.3 discrete time
again and again
and here is a alternative representation
of this base graph with what is known as
a Forney Factor graph
and so in this paper
they show that
[Music]
um
any base graph can be represented as a
Forney Factor graph
and any phony Factor graph
has a defined procedural message passing
algorithm
so actually a quite incredible
synthesis even in this 2017 paper
because it means if you if you can build
with these Legos
with this semantically interpretable
setting
then there will always be a procedural
technique to calculate it
no matter how convoluted this graph is
which is very important because you
could make um
um you could just add linear model
layers
but then you would start to lose
analytical guarantees very quickly
here now we're in the continuous time so
section 4.5 is a lot like 4.4
except it focuses more on the continuous
time model
just to only describe more on 4 15.
here we have our observations
Through Time
and that's a function G little G not
expected free energy
it's an observation its observations are
being emitted by a function of hidden
States and slowly varying causes V
which kind of plays the role of policy
in continuous time and a noise term so
this is our sense of reading here's EEG
measurements SPM measurements as a
function of
neural activity and sensor noise
and then the rate of change of neural
activity
is a function of
neural activity at that time and slowly
varying causes
so the mapping between uh data and
hidden states which is kind of analogous
to the a matrix is timeless
and then the rate of change of the
Hidden States x dot which is like X
Prime
is defined in a certain way and this is
like familiar structurally to those who
have looked at physics
generalized coordinates of motion
related to the Taylor series
approximation so the the black line is
the function true underlying function
here's our first pass approximation at
this time
evaluate the function and then just
that's you know y equals 4 is this line
then we have the second term
approximation which is
the value for I'm just making that up
and then the slope instantaneously
the third order approximation is going
to have
three coordinates of motion
the position
the velocity slope
and the acceleration
and then if you were to have another
term
taking it into another level of
exponentiation you would end up like
kind of probably coming back out
so that's how smooth approximation of
functions Works using the Taylor series
by evaluating higher derivatives
around the point of focus what is the
difference between the dot and the dash
yeah
the X so in in principle nothing in
principle they both mean rate of change
here
x dot and dash are being used
because
x dot
is
the change
function on hidden States neural
activity changing through time is x dot
so here is our estimate of neural
activity changing Through Time
here's the rate of change
of neural activity changing Through Time
x dot
Prime
but that is not necessarily X double dot
I hope that that's accurate
Jonathan
yes I think one of the things that
confused me most here is that he we've
got an F Prime of X Prime V Prime
um so certainly in figure 4.5 the prime
really does represent a derivative with
respect to Tau
and then within the equation here
it's just not quite clear you know what
what one is taking derivatives with
respect to and how many times like f
double Prime of X double Prime V double
Prime
it's just one it's one does not need
these two
um
well that that's what I'm
so to calculate the Taylor series here
you would want to include derivatives
but it's derivatives with respect to the
variables inside like with respect to X
yeah
yeah yeah and you have to be confused by
this no that that totally makes sense
I um
I agree anywhere where there's a
derivative or an integral
there should be clarification of what
it's with respect to
and that's sometimes done
but here Prime is being used just to
refer to the generalized coordinate of
motion
at that scale
okay then
writing down the variational free energy
with generalized coordinates
LaPlace approximation
this is something where there's a lot of
technical detail
but what the LaPlace approximation does
broadly also please correct me is
finds the single maximum likelihood
estimate for a distribution
and then parameterizes a negative
quadratic with the points being at the
maximum likelihood estimate
so for distributions with a central
tendency
LaPlace approximation can do really well
for distributions that are bimodal like
with two humps
LaPlace approximation is going to
identify the slightly taller hump
in its maximum a posteriori estimator
and then either draw a pathologically
narrow or wide quadratic around the
taller hump
Ollie oh okay
and more details on that
quadratic expansion around the posterior
mode mode most likely point of a
distribution quadratic expansion
drawing an upside down parabola
around that point
expanding some of those discussions from
the above into hierarchical models
re-viewing
the message passing
that we saw previously skyscraper on the
left unrolled Through Time on the right
in the context of generalized predictive
coding schemes
and a short summary
so definitely an interesting chapter
the mathematical details
Beyond
way back when
basically Beyond this point
really escalate fast
and there's also several boxes and
asides
like this message passing
generalized coordinates motion
and LaPlace approximation
all of which are
significant technical Concepts
so
a lot of challenges and trade-offs with
writing such a chapter
especially because this is like active
inference
chapter one overview chapter two low
road this is how we're gonna do it
chapter three High Road this is why
we're gonna do it chapter four
generative models of active inference
figure 4.3 discrete and continuous time
generative models
and then
there's a lot of technical details
so
anyone have any just overall thoughts or
questions on for
Jonathan and then anyone else
yeah I think I'd just to get more of a
sense of it I'd still be interested to
know more about the the Tau in G
um if anyone has any insight into that
when you calculate G
um
yeah does g still have a Tau index or or
is something else happening to it
yes good good that is noted if anyone
has a link or a thought go for it
otherwise that is definitely something
that we will need to revisit and improve
for for future cohorts Kate
um they're just a very general comment
like this was way over my head overall
but I was just wondering if in your
experience um
the
the textbook that you are kind of
working through with um mispronounced
his name name Joshi but the fundamentals
of active inference do you think there
will be some help in any of these areas
Ollie what's your what's your first
thought on that this is in reference to
sanjiv namjoshi's fundamentals textbook
that we are um like working through and
evaluating during 2023. so Ali what
would you say to Kate's question
uh yeah in my opinion I think it is way
way more helpful in understanding the
mathematical details and uh also in fact
uh the conceptual intricacies uh that
have been somehow uh glossed over in
this textbook uh but uh on the other
hand it is estimated to be about 600 to
900 pages long so uh yeah it is much
more expanded than this textbook and it
goes into uh into a very very helpful uh
detail
um expanding upon these
um mathematical derivations but at one
point I wanted to make is that
sanjeev's textbook is not strictly
strictly geared towards uh somehow
somewhat
mathematical derivation of these
equations but its main objective is to
use it as a practical tool in order to
model
these kinds of agents and in fact he
also provides some helpful Jupiter
notebooks in that regard but yes I think
it can be really helpful in Bridging the
Gap between this textbook and the
Practical side of doing things
yeah thanks ali um if anybody so the
book is not available yet it's not even
finished in writing if anybody wants to
be added to view
chapters and the code which are all in
Python which also increases the
accessibility relative to the Matlab of
this part hole
these
chapters
in a way that has not appeared in our
space before are tackling
the these statistical questions
so it is still like very much an
accelerated statistical learning curve
but as Ali mentioned it's less focused
on like well here's how you get from
here to here as just like a as a
analytical derivation consideration
and it's a lot more like
we're going to go step by step with
building stochastic simulations and um
so this is gonna it's gonna be a great
compliment and and Fields have many
textbooks so there's not just one right
approach
um
but it's been really encouraging to see
his work so if anybody wants like even
just access to the coda to review the
chapters
um please feel free to email us and
hopefully
in the coming year
we'll have more details on when it'll be
available
um
let us look ahead quickly to chapter
five
chapter five is the last chapter in the
first half of the textbook which is the
epistemic half of the textbook
so congratulations to those who have
continued on especially through that
second half of chapter four
which is definitely like
intense
to a comical degree
um and so carefree and Whimsical in its
writing style
which which
um
has its own kind of Comedy but we're
gonna have two weeks on chapter five
which is going to be a great return to
reality
and then
um
the final meeting will be on feedback
project ideas Terry I think we need to
approach to the maths pitched at a
seven-year-old yeah many angles on that
one is in the math learning group
we've explored these kinds of questions
and another approach is
a non-mathematics approach which several
people have investigated
how important will it be if we didn't
grasp all the details of chapter four
when we get to chapter five
irrelevant
chapter 5 picks up on a very different
note
remember that chapter four they even
said you could skip
said if you don't want to know the
technical details you can skip chapter
four which was again like it was like
wait but
we just took the low road and the high
road to our city
and then they're like you don't have to
go on the tour
if you don't want to
chapter 5 message passing and
neurobiology
um
Bayesian message passing
comes back
so again that box that we looked at
earlier the idea that every base graph
is sparse
not everything depends on everything
because of the sparsity of the Bayes
graph especially
there are some computational procedures
that are extremely effective
and interestingly
real biological systems also have sparse
connectivity whether it's the neural
architecture in the brain or whether
it's the interaction patterns in an ant
colony
in distributed systems
connections are sparse
they begin at the microanatomical level
with looking at neurons and their
connections
they focus on one of the most
well-studied neural tissues which is the
mammalian cortex
and the mammalian cortex has what's
called a columnar architecture
which is these six histologically
distinct layers of tissue so they look
different under a microscope
and the connectivity patterns in terms
of what actually sends axons where are
also essentially completely
characterized
and so in here we see the
tantalizingly realist alignment
of the histological
columnar microarchitecture
with Bayesian graphs
that have similar structure
in figure 5.2
they're going to generalize and kind of
coarse grain the columnar architecture
and now look at how different columns
communicate laterally
so we have like
hierarchical communication within a
columnar
unit and
connections across units this is kind of
like
um numanta thousand brain hypothesis
like a lot of work that is using the
neocortical architecture in search of
intelligent machines
so that's the neocortex
scenario
we're going to switch systems to the
mammalian motor chord
here we have incoming proprioceptive
data y
and descending predictions
those predictions and observations are
juxtaposed to form an error signal which
gets passed forward
so this is a continuous time setting
and here we can see action as resolving
discrepancies between Target set points
and proprioceptive input
now we switch to another mammalian
neural anatomical system which is
subcortical and the basal ganglia in
particular which is a dopaminergic
region
this region plays a role in policy
selection
check out the Oliver Sacks book or Robin
Williams movie Awakenings it's really
interesting and funny
here we see two different ways that the
dopaminergic tone
tilts the balance towards either action
selection which passes habits forward
or that kind of type 1 indirect policy
selection pathway
can tip towards a type 2 in economon
sense deliberative
free energy updated policy posterior but
we'll talk more about it
they talk about different
neurotransmitters inactive
they talk about how continuous and
discrete models can come together
and then they end the chapter
with bringing together those three
systems that were previously described
the columnar architecture in the
neocortex
the basal ganglia dopaminergic
decision-making architectures and the
spinal cord reflex proprioceptive
continuous time model
and they show how those kinds of models
can be integrated
to address some of our favorite topics
so it's a shorter chapter it doesn't
have equations like the previous ones do
so again congratulations to everybody
who made it through the more
think of it chapter four
and chapter five we're going to have a
lot of space for conversations about
like neurophysiology and the body
and it's just a good close to the first
half of the textbook
so
thank you all for joining
see you next week